

Raosaheb Thakare

Email: rnthaakare@gmail.com Cell -+91- 7350368842

Personal Statement.

3.5 years' experience in developing and executing Marketing strategies with the unique ability to understand the ongoing market scenario and customers trends using exceptional marketing communication skills, including ,Strategic planning and strategic leadership.

- Strategic planning and strategic leadership.
- Decisive: Capable of delivering quick solutions to the marketing challenges.
- Extensive work with all sources of media channels.
- Result oriented: Ability to achieve target within given time.

Objective statement:

Obtain a position that will enable use strong Sales and Marketing background, interpersonal skills and managerial abilities for achieving the company's marketing goals in the best possible way.

Professional Experience:

Assistant Marketing Manager (PAN INDIA)
PROMAS ENGINEERS PVT LTD (Designer, Manufacturer, & Exporters of,
BLENDERS, DRIERS, MIXERS, MILLS, COMPLETE TRUNKEY PROJECTS FROM CONCEPT
TO COMMISSIONING)

June 2018 to Still Date.

Job Description – Responsible for sales of Company's product to API, BULK DRUGS &

FORMULATIONS, COSMETICS, PIGMENTS, CHEMICALS, INSITUTIONAL & AGRO INDUSTRIES.

- To understand various applications of the company's products and Product line in your specific industry and be able to confidently recommend the products / product line.
- To Achieving the sales target / number and unit target for industry.
- To Work closely with each product managers to ensure that each product.
- To give regular inputs and updates on all customers / potential customers with regard to their plans and working of our existing machines
- To prepare action plan to develop business from your industry Understand customer requirement, suggest solution and submit offer.
- Solving customer problems and giving proper service to the customers and keep in touch with Purchase team.
- Generate leads and transfer lead in a actual sales.
- To work closely with the design team to ensure customer requirements are met timely. Negotiations with customers for closing deals.
- To Control expenses to meet budget guidelines
- To ensure high level of customer satisfaction Marketing and Strategy (for specific industry):
- Work closely with Sales & Product Heads for brand promotion and marketing strategy
- Maintain monthly Quotation hotlist

 Making monthly quarterly business plan & action plan for Self and Executive and Managements also

Teamwork:

- Worked hard as a team and as a good leader.
- Motivated the subordinates to work hard by assisting them.

Assistant Marketing Manager (South India) MACK PHARMATECH PVT LTD. (MFGRS .LAB & PHARMA EQUIPMENTS)

(Humidity Chamber, Cold Chamber, Deep Freezer, Incubators, Photo stability chamber, Hot Air Oven.)

July 2016 to May 2018.

Job Description –Responsible for sales of Company's Product to API, BULK DRUGS, FORMULATIONS, CHEMICALS, INSITUTIONAL & AGRICULTURE Industries.

Marketing Activities:

- Managed entire product marketing cycle Planning and applying the use of various sales strategies.
- Responsible for the sales of stability chambers and other and other lab equipment's in South India.
- Managed the Promotional budget of the marketing department for South Region.
- Initiated and coordinated advertising campaigns and promotional activities.
- Controlled all aspects of production line and Marketing Department
- Prepared the pricing strategy of the product for South India specially customized Products
- Interacted with media for promotion of the product Made key messages to attract the customer towards the brand name.
- Selected special products to be displayed at promotional events and exhibitions.
- Negotiated with the suppliers and vendors regarding distribution contracts.
- Maintained cordial relationships with the Customers and Focus on Upcoming new Projects.
- Visit To potential customers and Existing customers also and generate leads and transfer lead into actual sales
- Take quotation follow up from Department and after sending quotation take follow-up from the customer
- Attend Techno commercial negotiation meeting and general negotiation meeting with client
- Solving customer problems and giving proper service to the customers and keep in touch with Purchase team.
- Generate leads and transfer lead in a actual sales.
- Maintain monthly daily sales and outstanding payment recovery MIS report
- Maintain monthly Quotation hotlist
- Making monthly quarterly business plan & action plan for Self and Executive and Managements also,

Teamwork:

- Worked hard as a team and as a good leader.
- Motivated the subordinates to work hard by assisting them.

Market Research:

- Conducting frequent surveys among the customers regarding the requirements of products at present and estimating the requirements in the future.
- Analyzed current market trend and competitor information and focus on new projects.

Extra Activity:

Represented South India region in Following Exhibitions.

- CPHI-P-MAC INDIA 2018 Mumbai.
- PHARMALYTICA2017- Hyderabad
- PHARMA PRO & PACK EXPO 2017- Hyderabad
- ANALYTICA ANACON INDIA & LAB EXPO 2017- Hyderabad

Marketing Executive (Pune, Aurangabad, Nasik. Dhule)

Modern science Apparatus Pvt. ltd (Whole type Lab Solutions.)

Handling sales of Remi, Coslab, Electronics India, Borosil, Merk, RLCC, Finar, Polylab, Rankem, J-sil, Lab India.Gentlemen, Make Etc.

Feb 2015 to July 2016

- Responsible for Institutional and industrial sales of Nasik District....
- Target Pharmacy college and science colleges and pharma Industries.
- Full time role overseeing the operation of the sales and marketing Department
- Visit To potential customers and Existing customers also and generate leads and transfer lead into actual sales
- Collect the inquiry from the customers and submit to the Quotation department.
- Take quotation follow up from Department and after sending quotation take follow-up from the customer
- Attend yearly ARC negotiation meeting and general negotiation meeting with client
- Collect the order and submit to the Dispatch department,
- Solving customer problems and giving proper service to the customers
- Take outstanding follow-up from customers and collect outstanding payment recovery.
- Maintain monthly daily sales and recovery report

Trainee Marketing Executive

Nasik industries Manufacturers Association (NIMA)

May 2013 to July 2013

- Direct visit to the company and collect the data then editing data in Directory format
- Cold calling then arrange face to face meeting and Direct sales
- NIMA directory project work in Nasik District MIDC

Academic Project

Nahar Frozen Foods & Ice Cream Pvt. Ltd Malegaon Sinnar. Nasik.MH

A Study On Sales Promotion Strategy of Nahar Frozen Foods & Ice Cream Pvt. Ltd Applied in Nasik city.

Educational Qualification:

- MBA. (Marketing) from SNJB.K.B.JAIN College Chandwad (Pune University) in July 2014.
- BA. (English) from SN.JB. College ,chandwad with Pun University) in July 2012.
- H.S.C (Arts) from SNJB. College Chandwad (Nasik Board) in June 2009.
- Maharashtra Certificate Course in Information Technology (MSCIT)

Personal Information:

Date of Birth : 26/6/1991
 Marital status : Married

• Languages Known :Marathi ,Hindi, English

Address Permanent- At/P Ganoor, Tal- Chandwad, Dist-Nasik-423101	
I hereby declare that all the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.	
Date: / / 2018	Raosaheb Thakare